Sup y'all. We've got an amazing episode
for you today. We have as a guest Asset
Note's own Shubs. Shubs is a Recon
legend and the creator of really the the
most amazing recon tool the world has
ever seen in my opinion, Asset Note. Um,
not only can he do recon, but he also
does zero day research, CVE reversing.
He's just an inspiration in all areas of
book bounty. So, I think you'll get a
lot out of this interview, uh, because I
I got a lot out of it personally. Um, so
I I don't want to delay you too much
before we get into that, but I do want
to tell you about something really
awesome that came out of the critical
thinking community. A couple weeks back,
Joel mentioned this concept of like
creating a CVSS calculator that provides
ways for you to escalate your bugs. Um,
so how it works is you would go in
there, you'd put in your CDSS score
metrics, and it would say, "Okay, you
know, your bug's currently at a 6.8, but
if you figured out some way to affect
availability, you could probably get it
up to a 7.2."
Well, one of the members of our amazing
community, Beex, I think is the name,
how the name is pronounced, uh, on
Twitter, that's biio,
created just this tool, and it looks
super awesome. I've been using it for my
CVSs uh calculations and I think you
guys will really like it as well. You
can find that at cvssadvisor.com.
Now, as a part of this uh there's also a
feature where you can provide
suggestions for escalation types on
common types of vulnerabilities. It'd be
really awesome if you all headed over
there and uh provided some escalations
that that could be used by the community
to increase the efficacy of their bug
bounting uh bug bounty experience. Um,
so with that, I hope you enjoyed the
episode with shops.
If you include somewhere in your report
that says this is a zero day, they're
just going to tell you we don't accept
zero days. If you if you don't include
those words, 90% of the time they pay
you [laughter] surprisingly. So like
it's just found an RC in this.
Found an RC. It just happens to be there
in this product. Um, and they tend to
pay. Who knows? Like [music]
[music]
All right, Shubs. Dude, welcome to the
show, man.
Thanks for having me on here.
Of course. I I'm I'm really excited for
this episode because I I feel like I
have looked up to you forever as a bug
bounty hunter and now to be have you on
the podcast, be able to pick your brain
and talked about stuff, you know, at a
at a high level is going to be really
awesome. And I'm also excited for the
fact that um you are the most
well-prepared guest that we've ever had
on critical thinking. I always like send
out a uh a a doc, you know, hey, here
are some of the things we're going to
talk about. Please add anything you
think would be interesting. And people
are like, all right, sure, whatever. And
then I come back to the doc today and it
there's like a whole, you know, section
here. So, thanks for putting so much
work into prepping.
No, no, no problem. And like Justin, you
know, over the years, uh, and and you as
well, Joel, like you guys have both been
legendary in the bug bounty community. I
should be looking up to you guys as much
as you guys look up to me. So, I I
really appreciate you having me on here
and I've been following along um this
whole journey with your podcast and
yeah, it's it's it's honestly one of the
best things in our industry so far.
Dude, that just warms the heart, man.
And and I have to say I remember I just
have such a clear memory of sitting at
my desk at an internship that I was
working at um back in college. And I
remember reading
writeups from you, looking at the
original asset note, you know, the one
that before you actually started as a
company, right? And just getting so
inspired uh to build a reconnaissance
framework. And um and then, you know,
that sort of reconnaissance framework
that I built that that came out of that
was the thing that actually resulted in
me getting my first bug, which I used to
pay for my honeymoon. So, you know,
shubs, [laughter] you have very very
farreaching effects. Um, for those of
you that that haven't heard of Shubs,
um, one, you're doing something wrong.
Um, go to Twitter and do any or X,
excuse me. Um, and, uh, look at
anything. Um, Shubs is is one of the
most, uh, well-known book bounty hunters
out there. And one of the things that I
had on my list for today that I wanted
to talk to, you know, you about Shubs,
was um this this this piece that I think
is really unique to you um in that you
have a very um deep expertise in
reconnaissance, but you are also one of
the most talented deep dive hackers that
I I I've ever met as well. Right. I I
see you nodding there, Joel. You with me
on that?
Yeah. Yes. I mean there are so many
times I can think back just like even in
our like literal own experience me and
you working together Shubs where we've
done some insane deep dives on some
really really cool bugs and I think like
that's one of the best things that you
do. I think it's really relevant and you
see it a lot with the asset note work,
especially in the blog post. But you can
see like there's an insane amount of
depth and breadth at the same time that
goes into finding these types of bugs.
And the write-ups like really show sort
of that like that mind process that goes
on when you're looking into a bug and
you're exploring a system for the first
time and figuring out like how does this
work? What are the moving pieces? How do
I become almost on the level of an
engineer when I'm looking at this tool
to figure out where the holes are that I
can poke and start to pull things
together and build a bug out?
Yeah. So, I I want to pick your brain on
that, Chubs, because that's really
unique. So, I want to get sort of a
personal history of you as a hacker and
then also I want to I want to ask you,
you know, what parts of that personal
history do you think have led you to be
able to do both reconnaissance and deep
dive testing so well? Because it's
normally in my experience what I've seen
is one or the other.
Mhm. Yeah. No, for sure. I mean, the the
the history basically is like I was I
was just working at Hungry Jacks making
like $650 an hour. Hungry Jacks is the
equivalent of Burger King in in
[laughter] the US, right? And and like
the first bug I got from PayPal was like
1.5 grand, it was it was enough for me
to quit Hungry Jacks. The eight months I
worked at Hungry Jacks, I made like
$800, right? So at that point, um, bug
bounties were like ultimately going to
be life-changing and something that I
wanted to do. But
but but but the reconnaissance aspect
really comes from when I was competing
with, um, Nafy out of all people when
when we were growing up. We were hacking
together and I was competing a lot with
Nafy with reconnaissance and he often
had data sets that I didn't have access
to or he had certain data that I I
couldn't get. And this is where the
whole idea of asset note came out where
it was like you know what like I can use
all these open source data sets or or
data sets that are public and just get a
notification as soon as possible and
hopefully that beats the overpowered
data sets that he has access to. Right?
So that was the original idea for for
asset note and reconnaissance really
became um a passion when working on the
right games bounty.
The riot games bounty was something that
was just incredible when it came to
payouts and and resolution time. It's no
longer really like that unfortunately.
Yeah. But back then, um, back then they
would pay eight grand for a subdomain
takeover.
And that is a really ridiculous.
That's back then. That's that's honestly
the most I've seen a company at that
point in time pay for a subdomain
takeover.
And the amount of money they were paying
for critical bugs was incredible. 20 30
grand. It was really good. I think today
an equivalent bug bounty program would
be something like Epic Games. Um but but
back then um Right Games was really the
the forefront of this
way to really way to really stick it to
them sh you know like not only do you
say they're not good anymore but you
also say you know what instead hack on
their competitor like [laughter]
it's it's I mean unfortunately it's true
like I I mean I love right games and I
still want to submit vulnerabilities to
them but they don't have the resolution
time and the bug bounty amounts that
they used to have back then and I think
there's you know various reasons people
move on. There was an amazing manager
that worked back then um on the bug
bounty program. His name is David Rook.
I don't think he's necessarily managing
the bug bounty program anymore. I think
there's been internal changes and things
like that,
but just from a from a bug bounty hunter
perspective. These days, I don't spend
as much time on write games um as as a
bug bounty program.
Um
but but yeah, I mean that's where the
reconnaissance kicked off. That that was
the incentive to be good at
reconnaissance was so high at 8 eight
grand for a subdomain takeover. That's
something that, you know, really changes
your perspective on reconnaissance.
Mhm. Oh, yeah. Absolutely. I'd imagine.
So,
it's really funny that you that you
mentioned the whole aspect of competing
with Nathy because I I I had to check
because I did I I was pretty sure that
you changed your name, but your your
hacker one name now is Shubs. But when
you [snorts] started, when I when I
first knew you, your username was not
Nafy. [laughter]
Yeah. And it it was it was a funny
inside joke for a while, but I recently
changed it to Shubs because, you know, I
think times changed and stuff. We had a
lot of fun back then. competing. Um, and
yeah, I mean to answer your question a
bit more, Justin, about, you know, how
how am I doing the reconnaissance side
and also deep diving.
I guess all of this deep dive experience
really came when Uber as a program got
established.
Okay. So, when Uber got established,
I I had that in the notes. I was like,
you know, I've seen you deep dive the
heck out of Uber and I've seen you, you
know, do recon stuff on Uber, but a lot
of that is deep dive. And then, you
know, you did the recon and riot games.
So, like, you know, I I I did my OS end.
That's that I'm feeling good about that.
[laughter]
You're very accurate about that. And and
I guess the the thing that maybe people
might not know is the reason why I even
bothered targeting Uber so much and why
I spent so much time on Uber.
The reality is I had an ex-colague of
mine. His name is Matthew Bryant
and he moved from Bishop Fox to Uber.
Yeah. He's an amazing individual, one of
the best hackers I know. and um he he
moved from Bishop Fox to Uber and I was
like, well, how can I like stay in touch
with Matt? You know, let's just submit
bug reports to Uber and he can respond
to them. That's that's a it's a great
way to stay in touch. That's great.
So, um I really had this
Yeah, I had this personal connection
where I enjoyed finding vulnerabilities
in Uber at the and and seeing Matt's
reaction and seeing what he thought of
these vulnerabilities. So, um that was
how I initially got into Uber. But what
I found was uh the more time I spent on
Uber, the more necessary it was to get
deeper and deeper into the application
stack. And if I wanted to find more
vulnerabilities, I had to get
comfortable with things that most people
can sometimes be uncomfortable with,
which is like um really deep JavaScript
analysis work basically. um which which
a lot of people can shy away from
because they feel like it's just like a
three megabyte blob that they have no
idea what's going on and and it's so
complex and they don't know where the
variables what what references what and
how to find the API endpoints and and so
on so forth. So that's that's really
where it was and then suddenly at some
point Joel started working at Uber. So
at that point I was like that's even
more of an incentive to start submitting
more vulnerabilities to Uber, you know.
So, [laughter] um, it's kind of been
that common theme along the way.
Yeah, I'll pull up.
It's really funny you say that.
Go ahead.
No. Well, it's really funny that you say
that because usually when I have friends
who work at a company, that is like
number one reason why I won't hack on
their bug finding [laughter] program
because I just assume that they found
everything.
No, dude. You got to The inverse is
true, man. You got to like pull a uh
pull a Tanner and Pete Yavorski and like
submit a bug on Christmas Eve, you know,
that makes him get off and go to the
office. That's that's the real
friendships [laughter] thing right
there.
Um, no, there's so there's so much to
unpack from what you just said there,
Shubs. Um, one I would love to go in the
direction of talking about, you know,
your competition with with Nathy and the
way that you guys have helped each other
grow as hackers. And I also just want to
talk about and maybe I'll just I think
we'll go the first route, but I I just
want to acknowledge that um one of the
other amazing factors that makes you so
different than a lot of other hackers is
that your ability to stay in touch with
people and and like be involved in all
these various hacking efforts. Like I
feel like every person I talk to,
they're like, "Yeah, and then I was just
like popping these crits with Shubs and
then I was building this tool with Shubs
and then I and then but while you're
running a company, like that's the other
amazing thing." I'm like, [snorts] how
the heck do you even do that? Um, so and
I think that ties back into the nafy
thing, too, because, you know, I think
pug bounty has probably always been a
pretty social thing for you, right?
Yeah, for sure. I mean, collaboration is
is beautiful and I love it. And I
actually prefer collaborating over
working by myself. Um, even if it's at
the cost of half the bounty or whatever
it may be, at this point, I don't even
really look at the amount of the bounty.
Yeah, look at how much fun I'm having
from the process and with the friends
and whatever so on so forth. So
I mean the the first part that you
mentioned around um competing with Nafy,
I think that was really successful
because we both really motivated each
other at becoming better versions of of
hackers and and there were many elements
of reconnaissance that Nafy has been,
you know, extraordinary at as a hacker
and I've definitely been able to, I
guess, one up each other each time when
it came to write games specifically. So
that was something that we we we
definitely spent a lot of time on. Um
but when it comes to um being in touch
with all these people and and
collaborating with people, I think that
honestly there we just have such a great
group of hackers in our industry. Like
you know you've got the the Sam Curry,
the Brett, the Justin, the Joles, we
just got so many great people that you
want to spend time with, you want to
hack with, and there's not enough time
in the day. So, it's it's it's one of
those things where um you know it's it's
not been so difficult to stay in touch
with these people because most of the
time they're doing some really cool
stuff. Like if I just ask them like what
are you working on? Like what are you
looking at? And they'll be like I'm
looking at airlines today. I'm looking
at the point system. I'm looking at you
know whatever. I'm like oh that's really
cool. I want to hack that as well. So
wonder I feel that a lot of these
[laughter]
Yeah. Yeah. I have no idea who that
could be.
Yeah. For sure. And it's just it's Yeah.
That that's that's great, man. And and I
think your mutual admiration for all the
other hackers shows and that's why
everyone really wants to collaborate
with you, too. Um, so that's yeah,
that's really awesome. Um,
I think one of the other things that
that I've noticed is like because your
recon game is so
so good.
Um, like you know, you spent literal
years like building out
reconnaissance tools and that gives you
this really unique ability to find like
weird stuff or or like you know just
stuff that like really sets off that
like Spidey sense your hacker Spidey
sense. And that like often times I find
that I'll be having a discussion with
you that's like, "Hey, what are you
hacking?" And you'll be like, "Oh, I
just found this like weird thing. Um,
you know, maybe we can like figure out a
way to like get the source code or
something and then it just like spirals
off into this whole big tangent where we
end up finding some crazy bug." And
that just really speaks to like the
quality of recon and the and the the
amount of time that's gone into like
building these systems to find these
things because the signal is like
insanely high.
That's right. And and there's like it's
it's really weird because um I I often
struggle with this myself where it's
like should I go deep into an
application or should I spend all my
time on reconnaissance and nine times
out of 10 I usually find that if you go
deep into reconnaissance there's
something out there on some server in
like Dallas or something some random
place in the US or whatever or in like
some random country that's just sitting
there that's vulnerable that's connected
to their internal network that you had
no idea or it's within like four
directories deep or something or there's
something just crazy out there and um
that stuff sometimes is really fun to
find and and and it's it's great but I
also understand with sometimes on live
hacking events there's no other option
than going deep like for example we had
that PayPal event in Barcelona like as
much reconnaissance as I did on Venmo I
was not I was not finding anything like
that I had to go deep into Venmo and I
still didn't find anything deep into
Venmo
but like Joel like what you mentioned
about finding one of these really
obscure assets and going
That's really one of the best ways to to
to to get a critical in any company.
Like we did this for Facebook and I
remember we found this random subdomain.
It was like supernova something whatever
and it was running um terodissy pco IP
manager and I remember when Joel was cuz
one of the problems with with with with
this was we we obtained the jar file by
spinning up an AWS uh image of this in
the marketplace but when we decompile
the JAR file there's going to be a lot
of inconsistencies such that we can't
compile the project and I remember like
going to Joel being like hey man like
you're an expert at like Android and
Java and all this stuff um and I need
help like being able to debug this. I
have no idea if these vulnerabilities
are going to lead to anything, but I
need some help. And Joel like whips out
his ID. He starts fixing all of the
problems inside this Java code one by
one, fixing all the inconsistencies to
the point where he starts getting it to
compile, sets up a debugger port, gets
it debugging, and we just step through
the code step by step until we find all
these vulnerabilities. So, I remember
these these these memories where we've
got, you know, all of this this this
rich like research that that's been done
as a result. But, you know, back then
when I hit up Joel, I couldn't do any of
what Joel did at that point in time. The
the the the debugging, the fixing of
Java, all of that stuff, I I didn't have
the experience to be frank. And and
without Joel, there was no way that we
would have been able to confidently say
to Facebook that we had all of these
vulnerabilities. So,
definitely situations like that. And I
think the only reason why today I feel a
bit more comfortable with this stuff is
because of the work we do at asset note
with finding zero days and we've had to
become really good at this process.
Um
yeah.
Yeah. So so that's great and it actually
segus perfectly into a a section that I
wanted to talk to you about which is you
guys have done so much so much quality
research at at asset note. feel like you
know every month or every two months
there's a blog post coming out um where
you guys have done something really
amazing uh finding zero days in
enterprise software mostly um and I know
that you know I know that you do a lot
of that and I also know that Dylan does
a lot of this Dylan Pinder I'm sorry I'm
not sure if I'm pronouncing his last
name correctly but um you know it seems
like you guys have really found some
amazing BS together and one of the
common threads that I noted across all
this because I'm I'm not proficient in
this specific specific area is the use
of a dynamic analysis um you know of
hooking up a debugger to it and you know
stepping through the code and breaking
at certain points and stuff like that.
Um so you know it it can you talk to me
a little bit more about that process and
how that's changed your approach to
enterprise software?
Yeah, for sure. Uh I mean debugging is
almost necessary when when we're looking
at complex enterprise software.
Sometimes unfortunately it's just not
possible and and we we we don't have the
installation file or we can't install it
like some of the Oracle software that's
out there and it's just too tricky to to
get up and running. But
but nine times out of 10 we're looking
to get a debugger going because um most
of the vulnerabilities that we find they
can be really complex and without a
debugger we can't figure out exactly you
know what are the variables at a certain
break point how do we manipulate them to
get what we want um and and things like
that. So these days um most of the
projects that we debug from a I guess
just from a a dynamic analysis
perspective is mostly Java and .NET
projects.
For for Java we use Intelligj um which
is you know you can get the community
edition it works fine out of the box and
you can start debugging things. For net
we use Ryder and that's also from Jet
Brains and that's beautiful like
honestly Ryder you can attach directly
to a process. It starts decompiling
everything for you and you can start
setting break points quite easily. So
for for those two languages, that's what
we use. Um and I think um when it comes
to binary analysis, we obviously we use
things like GDP and things like that to
to do do our dynamic analysis.
Um but
yeah, Dylan um he's honestly um one of
the the best researchers that I've ever
worked with. Um we hired him.
He's great. He's he's so great that like
sometimes sometimes he's very quiet. So
sometimes he'll be quiet for six hours
or something and I'll ask him like,
"What's the progress?" person like,
"Yeah, I got an orth bypass or a shell
or an RC." I'm like, "Dude, you could
have told me earlier. I've been like on
the edge of my seat [laughter] this
whole time." You know what I mean? So,
so um so Dylan's sometimes quiet, but
he's he's very very good. I mean, his
background in the other room, you know,
if you're not hearing them, they're
getting into something, you know, like
[laughter]
Yeah. Yeah. And he's he's he's he's just
so multid-disiplinary. Um he has um such
good skills in Java and
Um, but he's able to get his hands quite
dirty with uh binary exploitation and
analysis as well, which is something
that's incredibly valuable for us. As
you guys have seen, like recently, the
Citrix vulnerabilities have come out and
it was like a race to patch diff them
and find the the rce. So, so without
Dylan, we wouldn't have been able to do
that work basically.
Yeah. No, he he seems like a really
valuable addition to the team and and
yeah, I'm always watching that that blog
very uh you know, hopeful for the next
one to come out. Do you have any any
teasers for us? Any anything you want to
tell us about coming up soon?
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. There was a
metabase pre-author rce that was
announced um around a week ago. So, that
that's that's the next thing coming up.
It's done by myself and an ex-colague of
mine. Um, and we're we'll be releasing
that on August 20. Uh, that's the
slated.
I saw you mentioning that in in Bug
Bounty forum
for sure. But the
has anybody somebody [laughter] posted
there like, "Hey, does anybody know
anything about this metabase RC?" And
Shubs just replies, "Yeah, Asset not
found that." [laughter]
Yeah, it was it was it was a really fun
bug and I think people are going to
really enjoy the chain cuz it was not
straightforward and our final exploit
payload has like maybe five or six
different tricks in one payload. So,
it's really really fun to fun to see. Um
but but um you know, we'll see. There's
already Chinese um researchers that have
reproduced the issue and they've posted
tweets of a blurred burp window of the
issue. So, if it drops before August 20,
we'll drop our blog post.
Gotcha. Wow, dude. That's awesome. I I I
love to get the little sneak peek here.
So, thanks for sharing that. That's
that's great. Um [clears throat] so, I
guess
asset node. So going going going to
Asset Note, right? Um just for those of
you that that aren't familiar, Asset
Note is the um I guess enterprise
security software that um uh I guess how
I'll let you describe it, Shubs. It's a
it's a reconnaissance. It started off as
a reconnaissance software uh in order to
help you do asset management, but it's
evolved to so much more.
That's right. So originally it was an
open source project that was just to
discover assets as quickly as possible.
But now basically what Aseno does is it
discovers all the assets that belong to
your organization on the external attack
surface and it continuously monitors it
for exposures. So it finds security
vulnerabilities and indicators that that
that organizations can use. But you know
like the the the difference between a
indie homegrown open- source bug bounty
tool and an enterprise product that we
sell to the largest enterprises in the
world. There's just so much in between.
So so different. [laughter]
It's just so different. And I and I, you
know, I mean, I see a lot of the the
frameworks out there that get released
and and all that sort of stuff and um
they're excellent, but I just think that
like to to sell to enterprises, there's
just so many demands that aren't even
things that are on people's minds when
it comes to building software um
necessarily that that has been very
interesting to to work through.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. So this product,
you know, has evolved from recon to to
asset management to asset management
plus vulnerabilities and then you know
also it seems like this research branch
has sort of come out of it. Now is is
that is that a supplement to the
product? Is that kind of how you're
seeing it or why did you guys decide to
start this research side of the of the
company?
Yeah, we we just identified like we
because we have access to all of this
reconnaissance data for all of our
customers including the technologies,
right? We identified that we have this
really unique opportunity to do security
research in a way that's targeted
towards our customers.
And basically our security research team
has maybe like two or three functions.
I'd say the the main function is
satisfying the needs of our customers
when it comes to when a new
vulnerability comes out like the Citrix
RC. Like we've we've got plenty of
customers that hit us up being like do
you have a check for this? And like for
a very long time I was the single person
on the security research team doing this
sort of work but after a certain point
there's just so many different new
vulnerabilities that are getting
released that we need to stay on top of.
We needed a research team. It was a
natural progression in inside the
product. Like we can't offer a great
like exposure scanning service if we
aren't staying on top of the new patches
being released, new vulnerabilities
being released. Even new nuclei releases
for example we need to stay on top of
because there might be something in
there that you know might affect our
customers.
But um the research branch also has a
second um purpose which is marketing and
you might have noticed that you know
like at asset note we don't actually
invest that much money into traditional
marketing like we don't have like crazy
campaigns for traditional marketing. We
don't have banners at blackout any
private rooms
none of that sort of stuff.
[laughter]
So, and I mean guys like there might be
a time in the future where we have to do
that sort of stuff as the as the company
progresses but but until now which is a
5year journey till now we've relied on
our technical um content to be the
biggest marketing that we do
and um I can say it's been incredibly
successful. Um I think from our
technical marketing we get probably the
most inbound leads I think if we could
attribute them all. Um, which is just,
you know, [snorts]
as a business it's not a bad model.
Yeah. No, that's that's amazing.
Go ahead, Joel.
Yeah. So, which one would you say sort
of drives the other one? Would you say
that your research team is more like
finding new things, reversing patches,
providing those vulnerabilities at like
as soon as possible to your customers or
your customers prompting you with, hey,
we heard about this vulnerability or
we're affected by this vulnerability.
Can you guys check for it? And then you
the research team goes and looks into
it. So, so we we we split up our
research stream into two different
things which is reactive and proactive
and um the reactive stream um is is
obviously like when customers reach out
or anything gets released on the
internet things like that we prioritize
reactive over proactive but we do
definitely still have a lot of time left
for proactive research.
So um I mean it's it's um for us the
number one priority is our customers and
what they what their requests are. So we
often even work with customers to get
access to software that we may not
typically have access to. But um that's
that's where we spend most of our time
is for customer concerns.
Dude, that's that's just what what an
amazing service. What an amazing product
you guys have developed there. And I I
love that it it it roots, its origins
are in security research in a in a
thorough understanding from a technical
level of what kind of stuff gets you
pawned, you know, and and and going
after that, like these CVE reversing um
you know, sprees that you guys have gone
on. And I and I loved that piece as well
about you breaking it up into reactive
and proactive. I think that's really
really um awesome. And I imagine on the
proactive side, you know, what what
you're doing for that is is you're
looking, you know, you're looking at all
of your your customers. You alluded to
this before, but you're looking at all
of your customers technology stacks. And
I mean, do you just pick the one with
the, you know, greatest number, or are
you looking for specific things like,
okay, this is Java, this is .NET, so I
know I can hook up a debugger to it and
have a better chance of finding a vault.
We we'll be ready to target anything
that has enough exposure for our
customers. But like for example, we
looked at C panel um and that's written
in that crazy
and that's like
crazy and written in Pearl and like all
these C binaries and stuff is honestly a
mess. Like as a security researcher you
go into that project and you're like I
really don't like working with this
project. But but ultimately we'll we'll
do anything.
But um the proactive side just to note
on that um while we look at our
customers technologies we're also not
afraid to look at technologies that our
customers may not be running now but we
might see it on a prospective customer
or we might see it on on the attack
surface in the future. Um and this this
is often just popular software. So if
there's any really popular enterprise
software that's usually a good enough
target for us.
That's that's awesome man. So so I guess
that's that's for you guys. you guys
have a great and we can sort of apply
these principles to bug bounty as well.
You know, we can look at the programs
we're in. We can fingerprint the
technologies and we can do the same
thing. Um, but specifically from the
CVE, you know, reversing perspective,
can you speak to how that could help a
bug bounty hunter and what kind of
skills they would develop as well as,
you know, what kind of results they
might see if they invest more time into
um zero day research or more
specifically CVE reversing.
And and just to tag on to that a little
bit, can you also maybe talk about the
amount of time it takes and sort of what
the input versus output looks like on
these types of things?
Yeah, I would say that um most CVE
reversing work doesn't usually lead to
an immense amount of bounties if there's
a lot of patching going on. But for
example, if you were to take if you were
to take the metabase research for
example, um then I think you could
potentially get a few bounties out of
that. Um I when it comes to inputs and
outputs I mean it really just depends on
every project. Every project can be you
know it like for example for Citrix
there was no information that they
provided in their advisory that would
even hint to us where this may be
located. It wasn't until we had other
people in the industry publish more
things like Bishop Fox that we saw,
okay, there's some more information
here. We can work with this and find
potentially what what they're referring
to. and and there's always the problem
of silent patches which is uh probably
the most frustrating part of this whole
CV reversing game um where they'll
release an advisory for an RC that's
critical but they'll patch like five
other things in that same release that
they don't talk about. So I mean there's
a lot of there's a lot of variability
when it comes to whether or not we'll
find what we're looking for in the CV
reversing project. Certainly, it's much
easier on Java based and .NET projects.
When it comes to binary based projects,
that's where it gets really difficult
because you're suddenly now you're
you're dipping the bins and there's like
just so much, you know, so much to go
through that's very esoteric and very
difficult to understand at a glance. So,
it's easy to miss things in binary
projects, but there's this intersection,
right, with with web and binary when it
comes to appliances like, you know, VPNs
and firewalls and things like that. And
we're we have to spend more time on this
sort of work because um ultimately these
products are exposed on the internet and
can lead to a shell on their network. So
by nature. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. From a bug bounty perspective, I
think the most profitable thing to do is
find zero days and report them to
programs. But there is a lot of
controversy around that as you guys all
know.
And let's let's uh let's start that
conversation.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Um I I mean I I personally I personally
think there's a lot of value almost like
what asset node does, right? Uh but from
a bug bounty perspective of getting your
hands on a a vulnerability with advanced
notice, right? Because um you know the
patch cycles, especially for some of
these bigger companies, um they're going
to be a little bit longer and and um
it's hard to track down all your assets
as as you know as the asset list grows
and grows and grows. Um, [clears throat]
and so, you know, by nature, if you get
a couple, you know, months head start on
on, oh, this this bone is going to be
released and, you know, just a heads up,
you're vulnerable. Uh, I think that adds
a lot of value and I think that's
something that companies should pay for.
Whether it should be, you know, their
full max crit or whether it should be,
you know, some bonus or some lower
amount. Um, that's, you know, to be
determined, I guess, by the by the
company. But, uh, that's my position on
it. Do you guys, what do you guys think?
I'm keen to hear what Joel thinks.
I mean,
yeah. Yeah. Let's hear Joel.
Okay. So, from a from a company
perspective,
yeah.
Um, it's a it's a it's definitely a
tricky situation, right? Like I I I see
both sides a lot better than I think
some other people in the industry do.
Mainly because I'm both a bug bounty
hunter and like a appseack engineer. So
from like the company perspective, it's
very tricky when you're using a vendor
product and you get that reported as a
vulnerability because the reality is
that all you can do is wait for the
vendor to fix it, especially if it's a
zero day. So there's no actual I mean
you can like turn it off or you know
there are like certain preventative
measures you can do but you can't
actually fix it until the company fixes
it. And all that you would be kind of
expected to do is tell the company, hey,
we got this zero day. Do you know about
this? And if the company says, "No, we
don't know about that." Then it's like
you're in a weird spot where you've kind
of ruined the researchers spoils and
also alerted the company and now the
company's like, "Hey, why don't we know
about this?" [laughter]
Um, and it but like if you don't report
it, then like you're kind of like
missing your ethical boundaries. So I it
it's very very tricky from a researcher
perspective. I think you should just
report it to the company and then go
ham. Like that kind of sets your ethical
liability a little bit lower because
you've told the company now it's up to
the company to fix it. If they fix it
really fast and they tell all their
customers and the customers update it
really fast, then good job. But you've,
you know, notified and now it's kind of
fair game for you at least, I think. And
then whatever happens happens, right? If
if companies start telling the the
vendor that their product is vulnerable
and they've been receiving this zero
day, then the that's kind of on the
vendor now because the vendor hasn't
fixed it fast enough or now the customer
is hearing about it. So I I think it all
kind of goes back on the vendor. But as
a researcher, the main thing that I
would want to do is make sure that I've
at least told the company and then spray
and pray, you know.
Yeah, for sure. I I I want to hear I've
got so many things I want to say about
that, Joel, but I want to hear Shubs. I
want to hear Shubs's opinion first.
Yeah, Joel, I agree with you. You
reported to the company first and then
you reported to the bug panty programs.
But man, like in the last few weeks,
I've even had a situation where, you
know, it's been really gut-wrenching cuz
I had this pre-author, reported it to
the vendor, then reported it to a
handful of bug bounty programs. And um
the mistake that you know that that that
was made was I didn't tell this vendor
that I had reported it to these bug
bounty programs specifically. And as a
result they they wrote this like email
to me where it was like you know
gut-wrenching and they were like you
know asset note became the best people
we knew to just those guys. And I was
like ah [__] like I didn't really mean
for that relationship with the vendor
but but this is the game. Like this is
this is the zero day zero day game. And
at the end of the day, what what what I
find surprising is I I mean, their
perspective on this, they they're
welcome to have their perspective, but
the vulnerability in question, if I went
to an exploit broker, I think I could
have sold it for $50 to $100,000
probably for that that vulnerability.
Now, in this case, it's really really
surprising because in the bug bounties,
I must have made like two or four grand.
It's like a very small amount of money
to be making from this. At the end of
the day, we reported the zero day to the
vendor for no cost. And this was zero
day research that we did that definitely
cost us money. So it was our
vulnerability that cost us money to find
and we report it to the vendor for free.
And then we reported to bug bounty
programs after we've reported it to the
vendor. At that point I'm really
struggling to understand where like you
know where we've gone so wrong in this
equation when ultimately we've we've
just tried to report it to programs that
have this issue on their attack surface.
I think there are a few nuances also
just quickly on on what Joel has
mentioned about this is where like you
should try your best not to report zero
in cloud products like SAS products onto
other companies because there's really
no resolution at all that a company can
do like you talked about the
preventative measures that's possible
you can add a W rule you can shut it
down you can segregate the network
things like that when it's like a an XSS
on a that's a zero day in
there's like very little that a customer
can do to prevent that from being
exploited on their their attack surface.
So that's where it gets trickier.
So So
it's really funny that Hold on.
It's [laughter] really funny that you
say that because I can think of one or
two instances, actually more than that,
where a researcher has reported
something and they say, "Hey, we've been
doing a lot of research and we have this
zero day in cloud product. [snorts]
Here's a giant link that just like pops
an excess or something." And you're
like, "Okay, now what?" [laughter] like
what do I do?
Oh man. Yeah. So, I mean like on one
hand I feel that and I and I understand
what you're coming from as well, you
know, Joel with like, okay, there's not
really a lot the company can do, but
wouldn't you still want to know like
like you know that that's where I kind
of say like when people put in their in
their policy that they don't want zero
day reports, I'm like that's really
silly. you know, maybe define something
that's like, all right, we'll pay a
medium for or maybe we'll, you know,
decrease the severity by one. So, if
it's a crit, you know, we'll drop it to
a, you know, a medium or, you know, but
something like that. But even in even in
cloud services, you know, with with the
way that same site cookies are working
nowadays, if you if you are able to
compromise a domain uh you know, a
subdomain within a company's, you know,
domain, then you are able to do so many
more different attacks than you would be
able to do before. You know, it's a
really it's a it's a real problem. Um,
and so that's kind of why I'm an
advocate for doing something like, yes,
we'll take the zero day reports, but
we're going to maybe lower the bounty,
maybe not lower the bounty depending on
the impact. And if we do have to pull it
offline, if it's an RCE on a VPN
appliance, right, you better pull that
[__] offline and just tell your
employees to to get, you know, a
different way into the company for that
time being because, you know, if you get
popped there, that's very, very high
value. And we all know anybody who's
ever conducted an external pen test
knows you know as soon as you get in and
you get to the or external to internal
pen test soon as you get in
that's it you know like there's it's
almost never segmented in such a way
that you cannot just get literal keys to
the kingdom once you get in inside. So I
don't know that's my thought on it.
Yeah. So, so Shubs, I'm curious if you
have any experience like on both sides
of like the delivery I guess of these
types of things, especially with like
zero day reports because I think one of
the important things is that if you're
reporting something in like a cloud
software or even, you know, an on-prem
software that is a zero day that you're
also giving them almost like a security
team would recommendations for how to
fix it since it's a zero day like how
can you prevent prevent it or protect
yourself and all that kind of stuff to
sort of ease that delivery. Have you
found that doing stuff like that helps?
Yeah, it definitely helps. But um I've
also found that if you explicitly say
that something is a zero day in your
report, you're less likely to be paid.
That's just like if [laughter] if if you
if you include somewhere in your report
that says this is a zero day, they're
just going to tell you we don't accept
zero days. If you if you don't include
those words, 90% of the time they pay
you surprisingly. [laughter] So like
I just found an RC and this
found an RC. it just happens to be there
in this product. Um, and they tend to
pay who knows like how this [laughter]
happened, but and this is more about the
bug bounty economic side of things and
the strategy side of things, but but
generally when it comes to um reporting
zero days, we we like to have a some
sort of remediation option without the
official vendor patch. Like one of the
things for us at Asetote, we don't put
any zero day in the platform unless
we've come up with a workaround. So for
for for a lot of things we can come up
with workarounds but when it's things
like VPN appliances no we we we we
cannot come up with a workaround that's
that good at least like we can come up
with sometimes firewall rules things
like that but many cases will actually
write like the patch diff for the fix
and we'll provide the patch diff to say
this is how you fix it if it's like
something in PHP or you know something
in Java or whatever else but but um many
cases we we can't provide any good
remediation other than like modifying
ing web.config rules, modifying your
HTTP server reverse proxy config, things
like that to to prevent access to
endpoints and things like that.
Yeah.
Yeah, that that's really interesting.
So, you mentioned bug bounty economics
and I wanted to dive into that a little
bit actually because um we had a really
interesting discussion recently in a
discord server with some other bug
bounty hunters about how there's
definitely sort of an aspect of
metagaming to bug bounty and I'm curious
sort of what your take is on that and uh
about sort of some of the bug bounty
economics that exists around how to I
don't know how to say this nicely but
how to make the most money with your
reports And do you spam or do you go for
only crits or like how do you what how
do you view sort of the bug bounty
economics?
Yeah, this is this is a really tricky
one. I mean um there are some things
that align quite well for the program
owners and bug bounty economics for the
bug hunters. The number one thing is
writing a a a [__] good report. Like
that's that's the number one thing where
both the the program owners are going to
appreciate it and from an economic
perspective you're going to make the
most money. So I I definitely focus a
lot on that. But there are definitely
times where look look like I haven't
figured out the magic solution yet
because every program is different. But
like I'll find like 20 xes, right? And
I'll be like how do I report these? Do I
report these one by one? Do I report
them in one report? Or do I report one,
wait, see if [laughter] it gets patched,
see if they patch all other 19, and then
report another one. So, so this is this
is the the hardest hardest part of like
this strategy in bug bounties because
you never know which direction it's
going to go in because you know on one
hand if you report all 20 separate
reports there's a slim chance that they
might pay all 20 reports right
if you report all of them in one report
they're probably just going to pay for
that one report. If you report one,
wait, report another after they've
patched the first one, there's a pretty
big chance you're going to get the
second one, third one, fourth one until
they figure out there's a systemic
problem with their with their software.
So, so, and this is really tricky
because this is where ethics come in as
well. It's like it's not just about bug
bounty economics anymore. It's about
ethics because it's like do you actually
want to secure the company? Are you
actually trying to improve their
security or are you just trying to make
money? And and if the answer is no, I'm
actually trying to improve the security,
then I would say option one or two is
probably better. Either separate reports
or one big report.
If you're just trying to make money,
then option three is clearly better in
many cases, like where you report
slowly, right? And and and this is not
something that hackers usually like to
default to. Hackers want to get their
money as soon as possible. They don't
want to be waiting for a year to get 20
xxes paid out. This only happens when a
bug bounty program has treated you
unfairly in some way or form in the past
where you've you've done this 20 reports
and they're like, you know what, we're
duping all 20. We're just paying you for
one.
Then in the future, obviously bug bounty
hunters are going to be like, you know
what, I'm not going to report the 20.
I'm going to see if you catch on. And if
if you do, then sure, you fix the 20. If
not, I'm going to get as much money as
possible. So it's it's this weird thing.
It's about like relationships,
economics, ethics all into one. just
about how you report bug bounties. Like
it's it's it's just it's crazy because
this is some of the stuff that goes
through my head when I I find a lot of
vulnerabilities for a single program.
It sounds like a very very specific
scenarios when you find [laughter] 20 20
xes. No, but I I think that was really I
think that was really well stated and
and I think you know the way you thought
through that is is really solid. Um
there's so many different intricacies to
it and there are going to be people that
are going to optimize for their money
and there are people going to be
optimized for security and bug bounty is
all about incentives right you're
incentivizing the hacker to hack on your
program and you know there's incentives
on both sides to maintain the researcher
relationship and that sort of thing um
and I think this sort of quandry is very
important um for the programs to address
in their policies right these are the
kind of things that that companies need
to start putting in their policies the
the piece of okay what happens if I have
20 XSS's do you want all of those right
away do you you know do you want all
those in one report do you want those in
20 different reports am I incentivized
in any way to put them in one report
versus in putting you know spreading
them out over time because at the end of
the day the company needs to you know
out outline that for the researcher and
so we can align our incentives and the
researcher might know hey I'll get paid
for like you know two and a half of them
or you know five of them or whatever
ever, but that's better than sending in
20 reports, which takes time and effort
and then getting duped back to one or or
the opposite of putting them all in one
report and then just getting paid for
for one.
Yeah. I'm also really curious how the
deep dive like when you deep dive a
program and you have a really long
lasting relationship like for example
with Uber, how does that change the way
that you report things? Because I know a
lot of times when people are really
really familiar with a program and
they've spent many years or many months
hacking on that program, they won't
report everything because often times
they'll realize that certain things that
may be lower impact or may not just be
like really nestled into the security
model of that company don't matter
enough to report, but they will matter
in a future report. And so they're not
they're they're making like certain
decisions where they're like I'm not
going to secure this this company with
this bug, but eventually I will secure
them with this and another bug. And how
does that sort of play a role in the way
that you report things?
Yeah, definitely a huge role. Happens
all the time. Things like um open
redirects or ids specifically um are are
major things that uh I will decide to to
to skip reporting in lie of a future
report. Like one example, if we think
about Uber, right? There's this huge
problem with Uber and idols where you
need to know the UYU ID of a user in
order to then discover further
vulnerabilities, further idols and
things like that.
Know anything about that Joel?
[laughter]
That that was definitely not the number
one impact reducing modifier that was oh
we have UU IDs so [laughter] you need to
not go for that. Yeah, but but but dude,
if I was going to find an idon and this
has happened in the past where I can go
from like an email or a username to a
Uyu ID then and it's just the UYU ID in
many cases. I sit on that until I can
make that even more impactful. So, I've
done this like uh for Uber in the past
where we've gone from and it's so great
cuz the P finally comes out and the P is
like enter the name of the person you
want all the PII for. [laughter]
I just take a video and it's like they
enter a name, they press enter, it's
like which user out of this us list of
20 users do you want to hit PI
and they enter that one and then
suddenly there's all the PII. So, so
that's that's the kind of pock that I'm
really excited about. But that that
takes like a lot of time to get to and
in many cases it does require sitting on
certain bugs that you find and and Uber
is particularly interesting like you
know just heavily brute forcing their
GraphQL schema to find all of these
really weird like queries and mutations
that can lead to these issues. It's just
it's been so incredible seeing the
transformation of Uber and their
technology stack over the last 5 years.
It's just gone from different technology
to different technology and now they've
ended up in like React, progressive web
app, GraphQL. That's like their final
and then they've got like, you know,
Presto DB and, you know, Pino Apache
Pino and like all this stuff. So they've
just, you know, really changed over the
years. Um, so it's been really
interesting to see what they they they
get up to.
Yeah. Well, and it's I think from a
program perspective, having something
like that is almost like keys to the
kingdom because especially if you have
reported that idor that like leaks, you
know, a UU ID for a user or something by
by like phone number or email address,
you can refer back to that report in so
many future reports and say as I
demonstrated in blank, it's possible to
leak this UU ID, which makes it, you
know, one step away. Or you can, you
know, if that report is still open, you
can report a bunch of other idors that
use a UU ID that then reference back to
your open report that leaks a UYU ID and
that can increase the impact of all
those reports. Um, and just like having
that knowledge of a private report that
that shows that impact makes it so much
easier to demonstrate impact for other
reports because it's no longer
theoretical. It's something that you've
actually done and you've actually
reported and the program now knows that
exists and it could exist somewhere
else.
That that's a really good point. I don't
think I've tried to refer to old reports
like that. I've always tried to find new
stuff to be like, "Ah, this this works
again." Um, but that that's that's a
really good point. I should
at live hacking events. That's something
that we did a ton where we would uh
we would go back and we would say, "Oh,
we know that this is possible." Like
when we're trying to determine impact,
what's like the worst case impact? Well,
we we know what those worst case impact
scenarios are on the internal security
side. And so there's like persistent
problems or pre-existing problems that
you know like automatically increase
impact based on a class of bug like if
it's an SRF you know that that SRF can
get blank data or whatever based on the
network conditions.
Yeah.
That is basically what you can do as a
bug bounty hunter is mentioning that oh
this is something that existed before it
can definitely exist again and the
impact has been proven.
Yeah, dude. We've we've seen that. I
I've seen that specifically in one live
hacking event. Um there was this
endpoint that leaked just all sorts of
IDs. It was actually leaking paths,
right? It wasn't it wasn't leaking just
the IDs. It was leaking the full paths
of anyone hitting, you know, various
endpoints. And dude, that bug got passed
around like candy at that event. It was
probably [laughter] It was probably
freaking, you know, worth hundreds
thousands of dollars in escalations,
right? because everyone was like see see
this report even if they didn't have
access to the report you know we would
say put in your report see this you know
report ID right and people would people
would reference to it and be like oh
that's where you you know that's where
you get the IDs from so those sort of
gadgets you know we sort of talked about
this a little bit on the pod before but
those sort of gadgets
super super valuable
um
okay cool we're we're we're getting
close to uh end of time here so I I want
to be I want to be conscious of your
time shs and and the block that we have,
but I have to ask, we've had a lot of
people that are interested specifically
in um buck bounty plus entrepreneurial
ventures, right? Um and I can't think of
anyone better than you to talk to about
this. So, you know, coming from being a
hardcore buck bounty hunter into um, you
know, an entrepreneur running a
successful company, can you talk a
little bit about that transition and
what kind of skills apply and what kind
of, you know, anti- synergies you see
there as well?
Yeah, for sure. I think um, one of the
the really cool things about being a bug
bounty hunter is sometimes you just have
to be willing to do anything that's
necessary to move forward. whether
that's reading 3 megabytes of awful ugly
JavaScript or whatever it may be, but
you've got to do the task at hand. And
um it's not that different when it comes
to running a business. Um when running a
business, there's just a thousand things
to do and and sometimes, you know, you
might feel that, you know, you you you
you could be spending your time on more
impactful things like security research
or whatever,
but at the end of the day, these things
still need to get done and we need to
move the business forward. So, as an
entrepreneur, all I can really say is um
two things really is pick the right
co-founder if you're going to co-ound
the business. And I'm very fortunate. My
co-founder, Michael, he's someone that
is, you know, excellent. He's he's a
hacker by trade. Used to do a lot of iOS
hacking and he has a ton of experience
in enterprise sales. He has a ton of
experience in running a sales team,
running teams in general, doing
management work that I had no experience
in. And um without my co-founder,
there's there is no way that that this
business would have been possible. and
vice versa um is what we say to each
other all the time.
Um but the second thing is be prepared
to do anything that's necessary. Like
there should be no work or no ego that
prevents you from being from doing
things that that that you might not want
to do at the end of the day. Like um
running a business is just about you
know providing a a really good product
or service to your customers and there
should be nothing that stops you as a
founder from being able to do that um
when it comes to ego or comes to things
like that. So, you know, just to give
you an example, today I still respond to
maybe like 80% of our support tickets,
which is like, you know, wild. Like, why
am I responding to support tickets?
[laughter] I'm 5 years in grind.
Oh my gosh,
it's such a grind. It's crazy. It's so
much work. But um and and sometimes it
can be you know quite difficult to to to
respond to all of these. But I know
sometimes that one of the superpowers we
have in being this small company that we
are is if we provide extraordinary
support to our customers
that's one reason why they're not going
to leave us for one of our larger
competitors like a Microsoft or a
PaloAlto or whatever else. Um and the
other thing is I'd probably say lastly
is just stay in touch with with the
engineering side of all of this. So if
you are a technical co-founder um you
should still be able to write to the
code base if you want to 5 years down
the line. You shouldn't like you
shouldn't as a CTO let's say for example
you shouldn't lose touch with the
engineering side of things like you
should still be able to contribute to
the project and be able to make changes
where necessary or at the very least
understand what's going on. Um, it
shouldn't just be all someone else's
responsibility and now you can do CTOE
things, whatever that means, right? So,
there's there's there's definitely that.
And sorry, last thing. Titles mean jack
[__]
Keep them coming, man. Keep keep it like
titles mean jack [__] Like
my my co-founder, he's CEO. He's he's
he's leading the company. I'm CTO.
We never saw each each other as CEOs as
CTOs. We were never that before the
company started. The titles mean jack
[__] We're willing to do any work
that's necessary to get this business
moving forward. You know, my my my
co-founder often does product design
work. He does, you know, a lot of lot of
different different pieces in in this
business and and so do I. And that's
because as a startup, we we have to be
able to be working in this capacity to
to move things forward. If if people
start thinking, oh, I'm just X. I only
do X at this company. Then then suddenly
you're you're you're you've got you're
restricted by what you can achieve. Um
and most of the time if you put your
your mind to it you'll be very good at
something eventually. You might not be
amazing event in the beginning but uh
with more experience you will be very
good.
Um so I guess those are my my my common
points and I think also I just want to
lasting note that there's a lot of luck
required to to actually be successful.
Like I'm not going to discount the
amount of luck we had when we started
asset note. it was the right time that
the industry was starting to look at
attack surface management. We we started
to build this whole notion of attack
service management and and whole segment
was developed as a result and people
started selling this product. We had a
lot of competitors that also came into
this. We had large companies that came
into this like Mandant and Google and
Microsoft with Risk IQ. So there was a
timing element to this that was not
predictable. There was a lot of luck
involved. even going back to the very
beginning of asset note. I was about to
abandon the project and we had Matias
Carlson um who you know he's been in the
bug bounty community for some time. He
reached out to me and he said your
project is amazing. We should continue
work on it. And he got his girlfriend
who was a project manager at the time to
manage the project with us. Without him
I wouldn't even have continued like
building this. So the amount of luck
that was involved to to to get to this
point is just monumental. Right. So it's
something that I always recall. Um, it's
not just about the hard work and the
effort. There is a certain amount of
luck involved in all of this as well.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I I think that's so
true. I mean, even with my own career,
like the whole reason I'm in Bug Bounty
at all was because I happened to do CTFs
and I got to like a CTF championship and
one of the vendors who was sponsoring it
happened to get my resume and then they
were like, "Hey, do you want to
interview?" And I happened to interview.
And the person who sat across from me at
my desk in the office in New York City
was Cool Boss who was like a Facebook
hacker like way back in the day and he
was like, "Hey man, you should do this
mobile CTF." And I was like, it's all
luck. You know, it's like like I just
happened to have this guy across from
me. There's, you know, I think there
this happens so often in life where you
see like big case examples where
there'll be like some company that like
started from nothing and just like
became something like Aset, right? like
just like a little side project that
just like developed and developed and
became this huge huge big like vendor
product. And um you know there's just
like so many other cases where that
didn't happen and you have to
acknowledge luck if like you're going to
like be realistic about like how you got
there, you know?
Yeah. And for all of you people in the
comments, you angry people in the
comments that I can already hear saying,
"Man, I'm just not one of the ones that
has luck." You [laughter] get luck. You
get luck by doing [__] You can create
your own luck. You you get luck by
putting yourself out there and making
opportunities. You get luck by having
friends like Matias who who will, you
know, help you when you need help. You
get you get luck by taking a step out
and making that company, right? And and
failing and then moving on to the next
company and you know it. So it's
possible for anyone for sure. But when
we look back at it, it's very easy to
see all of the places where in our
career we could have gone different
trajectories. Um, and that's just that's
just what a blessing that's that's the
ride we've got, right?
Yeah. Yeah. It's amazing.
Um,
and I mean that's like how we know each
other, too. It's all just like luck,
[laughter] you know? It's like the
chances that we even like, you know,
cross paths at these live hacking events
and like, you know, it's crazy.
Yeah. So, so that was a great answer,
Shubs. And I I I really it almost brings
brings a little bit of a tear to the eye
to hear you talk about the whole
journey, uh, you know, that you've been
on for this whole time with Acid Note.
Um, it's really really cool. Um, I I did
I did want to go back to the the
question and I wanted to ask about again
about those anti- synergies. Do do you
and and you know if nothing comes to
mind, no worries. We I've got plenty of
other things I can pick your brain on,
but is there anything that a bug bounty
hunter uh or a hacker should should be
aware of that might be ingrained in
them? it might be a default for them and
then as they transition into
entrepreneurial stuff that they need to
be aware of that's different in that
area that might cause a problem.
Yeah, sure. I mean that there's
definitely some things like I think you
know I think one of the things is um as
hackers we we like to be very pragmatic.
We like to think logically. We like to
think step by step sometimes. Um there
are many cases when it comes to sales,
customer support or negotiations where
this sort of mentality, it can work, but
it may not be the correct thing to to do
in in whatever hand you're dealt. Like
sometimes um you've got to rely on gut
instinct. You've got to rely on, you
know, different ways of approaching the
problem that may not just be approaching
it step by step. Like for example, if
you're negotiating, that's definitely
something where you can't just
capitulate to everything that that they
want. You have to think a bit more
creatively of how you can get to a deal
without necessarily being in a position
where you've just cap capitulated to
everything. So there is like a different
type of thinking sometimes, especially
even in customer support responses. Like
yes, you might have a bug in your
product, but you can't always just go to
your customer and say, "Yes, we've got
this terrible bug in our product. we we
have to be a bit more strategic about
that. We have to think about you know
what are we doing to fix this? When is
it when is it going to be fixed? How are
we going to respond in a way that you
know minimizes the customer freaking out
about this bug in the platform for
example. So there are there are these
different things but I think a lot of
this um I think you know even being an
amazing bug bounty hunter spending a lot
of time in bug bounties before I started
my company I was still so underprepared
for what the 5 years that have brought
me this company in in this company and
there's just so much that I've learned
on the sales side the business side and
just generally uh running this company
with my co-founder I've learned all this
stuff because uh my co-founder has this
wealth of experience that he's brought
me into and I've been able to experience
it and and iterate on it with him.
Um, but you know, I I just think that
it's really important to to recognize
that you do not know everything about
running a business and be okay to look
for help or to seek help or to get
advice in certain areas that you may not
be so good at. There's this whole ego
element that I keep coming back to and I
know a lot of hackers can tend to have,
you know, sometimes bigger egos and and
if you want to run a business and it's a
small business, this ego stuff doesn't
usually work that well unless you're
you're the one who's just doing all the
sales at the end of the day. But if if
it's not sales, the rest of the
business, it requires this, I guess,
this acceptance that you do not know
everything. And you either might need to
learn about something, you need to read
about it, you need to go to someone, ask
for advice,
and you shouldn't be afraid to do that.
Um, not everyone's advice is going to be
golden. You don't have to take it. You
just have to listen to it, see what what
what you think, and move forward however
you feel.
Yeah, dude. That's great. In in
hindsight, were there any things that
you think you could you could have or
should have prepped better before, you
know, starting a company or things that
you'd wish you'd read or anything like
that that outside of like the people
aspect like, you know, were were there
things that you in in hindsight wish
that you would have learned? Yeah, I
wish I would have uh understood the
market a bit better and and done a bit
more um analysis with prospective
customers about what they're looking for
because um when we started our business,
I remember saying to Michael, my
co-founder, I said, you know, the the
minimum tier for asset node has got to
be like 1,000 assets or 2,000 assets. We
only sell to large enterprises. But lo
and behold, like now we have so many
customers that have 200, 300 assets on
the internet, right? Right? So, like
that was like a complete misjudgment
from my part about, you know, what we're
what we're selling and who we're selling
to. And and these deals are still
worthwhile. Even at 200, 300 assets,
they're still worthwhile deals. They're
they're profitable. They're they're
they're great for us. Enough of them.
We're making quite a lot of money,
right? So, initially, I didn't even
understand, you know, what the the plan
of selling this was and how we were
going to sell it. And I feel like
Michael and I, we had to come up with
different strategies of like different
business models as well uh that we had
to come up with over time where we
landed on one finally and that's worked
very well. But I wish some of the stuff
I did before even incorporating the
business, you know, like there was some
stuff like this where I'm sure I could
have reached out to some friends of mine
and been like, "Hey, I'm thinking about
starting this. What do you think about
this business model? Like this, would
you be comfortable paying this for this?
How much would you pay for this? what
would this look like if it was in your
organization? Some things like that
would be very useful because we were
under the we had many assumptions about
how we were going to sell this, what it
would look like that ultimately were all
proven wrong uh with with running the
business and realizing, wow, a lot of
people we're talking to, they don't
actually have 5,000 assets on the
internet. They have like 300 assets or
something. Um, but then I guess the last
thing is um, and this is specifically
for bug bounty hunters and hackers. If
you want to build a product, spend a lot
of time becoming good at engineering
because engineering is [__] hard.
Like we we we think that hacking is is
hard, which is great. I agree with you.
Hacking is hard. Engineering where
you're building a reliable product
that's consistent and and and is is, you
know, performing how you expecting it to
perform, that is harder than hacking.
like that that that is literally the
hardest [__] I've done in my entire
life. And and people on my team who deal
with this on a day-to-day basis, our
engineering team managed by Sean,
they're the people that today are
dealing with this problem still for all
of our customers. And and this is by far
the hardest, I guess, thing that I had
to do in this 5-year journey was go from
being a good a relatively good hacker to
being a good engineer. And I still don't
feel like I'm there yet when it comes to
engineering. Like I still feel there's
so much more to learn in engineering.
It's never ending.
Yeah.
And I'm sure it's the same in bug bounty
hunting. But but this is definitely
something that I learned was engineering
is very critical to this.
And and like you said in the beginning,
it's it's not just scraping together
some scripts like we do in bug bounty,
right? You know, you're you're you know,
sgvping files back and forth and your
Python janky Python scripts aren't going
to get you to a reliable enterprise
product. So there's I'm sure there's so
much more there and we actually do have
an episode coming out with Sean. Um I'm
not sure if it'll air before we air this
one, but uh that's a that's absolutely
amazing episode as he talks about, you
know, what it looks like to engineer,
you know, this huge massive beautifully
architected recon machine that you guys
have put together. Um and all the
different pieces, you know, in the way
that it integrates together. So, um,
with in light of that, I was going to I
was going to ask and I asked Sean the
same question for the hunter that is
building a a reconnaissance setup now.
Um, you know, you having gone through
all of the, you know, many many problems
of of, you know, that you faced building
asset node, what what kind of advice do
you have to to the bug bounty hunter
that wants to build a a continuous
reconnaissance platform?
Yeah.
For their own use in bug bounty, just to
be clear.
Yeah. Well, I think like Justin, I
remember you came to me um a couple
years ago and you said to me, "Hey man,
I'm seeing all these people move to
Golang. Like, do I need to move to
Golang as well? Is this is this the
right option to make?"
I rememberation.
Yeah. And it was just like cuz I
remember at that point I was maybe 2
three years into the asset note um
adventure and we had migrated everything
to Golang from the very beginning. So I
had experience working in your stack
that you're familiar with which is just
like basic Python, you know,
everything's pretty straightforward. you
can understand it without too much
complexity. Whereas our Golang stack for
our enterprise customers which can get
quite complex with the number of
microservices and things going on.
I remember saying to you like choose
whatever you're most comfortable with
and what you can iterate in quickly on
it. Doesn't matter if it's Golang or
Python or whatever.
It could be Visual Basic like Eric does,
right? It doesn't really matter what
language it is.
But but I remember you were like really
happy with that because you thought that
you had to move to a different language.
You thought that you were put into this
position where the industry is moving
and the industry is changing languages
to every everything in Golang for
various reasons. So I have to do it too.
And to be frank I was the one in that
position when I started as I decided to
move to Golang. There are many benefits
that we got out of that but I'm sure if
we worked hard enough we could get
something working in Python as well. Um
it's it's not really the the distinction
of how good the product is going to be.
And I see I see this trap a lot with you
know people will rewrite things in a new
language like they'll say oh there's XY
Z tool in this language I'm going to
write it in Rust now because Rust is so
hot right now and everything is amazing
in Rust but the outcomes are usually the
same like usually the outcomes are very
similar or the same sometimes there's
speed differences acceptable I
understand but at the end of the day are
you going to learn a whole new language
to get that bit of speed difference or
are you going to build your systems in a
language you're comfortable with that
you can iterate quickly on. So that's
definitely one of the advices that I
would give. Um the other one would be
like really think about your data
sources. Um as much as I would like to
say that you know our reconnaissance
techniques and and all of that are a
huge contributor, there's also a huge
element where the data that we have
access to is just overpowered compared
to other uh other people's data sources.
So that that sort of stuff. If you start
looking at things like passive DNS, if
you start investigating these things and
start understanding where you can get
these data sources, what these data
sources look like, how much you're
willing to pay for them, you're suddenly
putting yourself at an immense advantage
compared to almost every other bug
bounty hunter out there. And um I think
one last thing is um just have an
environment where you can quickly
iterate code on. When I was first
building asset node, I did all of my
programming in the equivalent of GitHub
code build. So back then there was
something called Cloud9 and I I used
that to do all of my iteration. It was
so quick like I was building so so
quickly. Today you've got things like
code spaces I think sorry in in in
GitHub. That's an equivalent of what I
was using back then um when I was
building the very first iterations of
asset. No.
Wow dude that was just a a treasure
trove of of advice there. Thank you so
much for sharing that. And I I remember
that conversation very clearly and I ju
I left that conversation like you said
ecstatic, you know, with the result of
what you said and it served me well for
the rest of the time, you know, that I
was in the recon game like being able to
quickly develop code in Python. It it
was it was invaluable. And I think also
one of the great things that that just
came out of that conversation for me was
appreciation for that, right? Because
like if I had gone down the other route
and I and I had, you know, written all
this Golang code, I might, oh man, I I
used to remember when I used to be able
to write code, you know, off the top of
my head without even thinking about it
in Python. That's that's great. But, you
know, and then I would have earned the
ability to like, you know, um appreciate
Python, but without having to go that
through that difficulty and that route,
you made me aware every time I wrote
Python code quickly how much of a
blessing that is and how much of a, you
know, of a win that was. So, thank you
so much for your advice, man. that that
really that really made a big difference
in my recon game.
No, for sure. I'm glad you stuck with
it. Um, for sure.
Yeah. Um, okay. So, I did have a couple
other things. Joel, did you have
anything else on that topic before we
swing back into some technical content?
No, no, let's let's go back into it.
Okay. So, I I did have a couple more
things that I wanted to ask. Um,
specifically regarding IIS, um, which is
your bread and butter, it seems, right?
you've done a lot of you've done some
videos on IAS stuff which we'll link in
the description and um what can you tell
us about hacking IAS servers. What what
do you have for the people?
Yeah, for sure. I think I think the
second you see an IS server, you should
thank God because it's the easiest thing
to hack out of all the other web servers
that are out there. [laughter] You
should be grateful. You should be
grateful that you you've come across the
presence of an IAS server. You see that
blue page that comes up when you hit an
IAS server? That that should be your
your point in time where you think I'm
going to find criticals on this.
Oh my gosh, I love that.
Because 90% of the time like like guys,
if you think about every other web
server technology, which other web
server technology lets you guess partial
files and folder names? There's nothing
out there like that. Like that that's
just ridiculous. And this vulnerability,
this issue has existed for like 10 years
plus. like it's been around for so long
and it still works on the latest version
of IAS. Like this is not even something
that they're thinking about seriously
fixing in future versions so far that
I've seen. So there's that, right?
You've got the ability to see partial
file names and folders. With enough
reconnaissance, you can figure out the
rest of those file names and folders by
doing some fuzzing so on so forth. Then
there's all this other stuff that
happens with .NET and specifically with
IIS and net where you are able to get a
shell if you get local file disclosure.
Now if you if you if you get local file
disclosure and you read a webconfig
file, it has the machine key, the
validation key, you're able to escalate
that from just that to to command
execution. Again, the the only solution
for this is you start storing these
values in the in the in the Windows
registry instead of the web.config file.
90% of the time companies are storing it
in the web.config config file and this
is something that you know often leads
to command execution once you get local
file disclosure.
Then there's the other aspect of this
where when you when you audit net um
products you've got to deal with this
whole idea of Windows shares and Windows
domains. So let's say you find an SSRF
that SSRF on a server on a net product
is much more than just reaching a web
server nine times out of 10. If they're
using path.join,
then in path.join, you can just do back
slashbackslash uh and and put in like a
Windows share back slash C dollar sign
backslash. And suddenly because of the
Windows APIs that are being used for
these network requests, Windows
willingly shares the NLM net NLM hash
with your server. So you run responder
on your server and suddenly you've
escalated an SSRF to a critical much
more critical than just being HTTP
requests. So there's stuff like that.
Then there's like, you know, I guess
there's also this this also this amazing
thing with .NET and IAS where there's
like a thousand different ways to drop a
shell. Like when you drop shells in IAS
and .NET, you can drop shells with
web.configs, with ASCX files, with ASHX
files, with ASPX files. You can drop
shells in so many different ways. It's
it's beautiful and it's really great to
be able to to to hack on on on net is
servers.
And one last thing that I love,
one last thing is if you're exploiting
an xxe in in an int application, there
is an xxe payload that is universal for
Windows that uses a a DTD file that's
within the Windows file system that's
always present in the Windows file
system. that will nine times out of 10
let you leak file contents when you
probably shouldn't be able to.
So these are all the different things
that's that's sick and I I want that
payload. We're I'm going to make a note
right now. Get get the exoske
uh because that that seems really
helpful. I've seen some stuff floating
around but it'd be nice to have it here,
you know, and link it down in the
description for the people that are
interested. Dude, that that was such a
treasure trove of of knowledge. I I feel
like, dude, I'm so lucky to be able to
have you on here because I just like
throw a little like, you know, question
out there and then there's just like
boom, gold, boom, gold, boom, gold. And
we were actually just talking about the
um, you know, the the share paths last
week and how crazy it is that you get
those NLM hashes. Um, and and that you
can interact with shares, you know, when
you have SSRF as well. Um, so that's
that's really cool, really cool stuff.
Um, and definitely for those of you that
haven't hacked on IAS stuff, check out
short, uh, check out short scan, um,
Bitquirs, uh, you know, till day
enumeration tool and then also read all
the writeups that we'll link below, uh,
for shubs on IAS related stuff because,
um, like you said, man, I get excited
when I see that that blue page and I
think most other hackers, uh, should as
well. Um, that's that's all I had on the
list for today. Um, Shubs, do you have
anything else you want to you want to
share or anything you want to talk
about? Where can we find you on on
socials as well? [snorts]
Uh, just two last things I want to share
and then we can wrap it up.
Great.
One of them is when you see the blue
page on IAS, do not skip it, please.
Yes,
there's something there. Like there's
there's no reason they've just spun up
an IS server for no reason. Like like
they wouldn't just do that. Most
companies have something there. There is
something there. Please keep keep
looking. Keep finding it. Whatever.
there's something there. And the second
thing is um just one other lesserknown
technique in IAS is virtual directory um
virtual like uh path traversal to
traverse into different virtual servers
via virtual directories. So in IAS you
can set up directories that are pointing
to different servers and if you use path
traversal within those directories you
can see the web route of different
servers. This is something that I found
um quite common in IAS deployments that
are complex. So they'll have / SSO
pointing to 10.1.1
and but it's pointing to 10.11.1.1 SSO.
So you can go SSO do percentage2f and
then that will route you to 10.1.1 to
the dock route.
Ah okay. So it's you're path traversing
on the backend server in the reverse
process.
That's right.
Okay.
That's right. Yeah. This is similar to
Sam Curry.
That's an IIS behavior specifically.
Yes, this is an II behavior
specifically. This is very similar to
Sam Curry's secondary context work,
right?
Um but but but then this this can lead
to a lot of crazy vulnerabilities
because in many cases they don't expect
you to be able to access the dock route
of 10.1.1 and you can just brute force
and find whatever you want and and and
and go from there. So
that's the last tip that I I don't think
is publicly talked about that much. So
just want to give that to your audience
as well. But besides that, you can find
me on Twitter um as infosc_u and yeah um
uh if you need anything you can reach
out to me via Twitter.
Dude, that's that's super clutch. So do
you know off the top of your head
whether the uh short name enumeration
technique also works on that backend
server then through the
It does, dude.
It does. That's it's beautiful. It's
Yeah,
that's amazing. I got to I got to check
that out. I'm definitely going to look
for that. uh for future for future is
servers that I see. And and guys,
remember if you see the blue page, go
after it. That's that's Shub's takeaway
that he wants you to have from today. Um
I need to go back to my recon data now.
Same, bro. Same. All right, infosc AU on
Twitter or X or whatever you want to
call it. Um Joel, you got anything else
you want to shout before we bounce?
No, that's it. I mean, thanks. I mean,
thanks for doing this. It's always a
pleasure to talk with you and just the
wealth of knowledge that you have is so
awesome. [music] So, I'm glad that we
were able to share just like a little
little bitty piece of it. Thanks for
having me on. Really appreciate it.
Peace.